Omar Al-Weli

076-878 32 44 omar.alweli5@gmail.com 281 52, Hässleholm, Sweden

PROFILE

Software Engineer with experience in Object Oriented software development. Driven by finding the most optimal solutions for software problems. Adept in communicating and working with diverse teams. Quick learner and always enjoy learning new technologies and things.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Software Engineering, Blekinge Tekniska Högskola

6/2020

- Research Interests: Software Engineering, Requirement Engineering, Algorithms and Data Structure.

Bachelor of Science, Software Development, Kristianstad Högskola

1/2015

- Focus: Android Development, Web Development, Software Architecture, Software Testing, And Databases.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Lime Technologies

01/2021 - Ongoing

- Working as a part of the add-ons team and is one of the team members who are responsible for specifying, describing, and creating issues/tasks for each project.
- Coding tasks, fixing bugs, solving coding issues, writing features, and reviewing code in both Python and TypeScript for several web application projects.
- Working with UI/UX to create a functional yet visually appealing products.
- Developing and presenting/demoing features and solutions for the rest of engineering team and senior staff.
- Writing backend and frontend tests.
- Working with GitHub actions and version control and is responsible for two Git repos.

PART TIME WORK EXPERIENCE

-	Local tech and software repair and maintenance shop	03/2017 - 06/2018
-	Health sector work - Helgedal Hemtjänst	06/2018 - 01/2019
_	Administrative and assistance work in a local theater - Kristianstad teater	2009 - 2013

Skills

alls			
-	Solving Problems through Software	-	JavaScript/TypeScript
-	Object Oriented Programming	-	C#
-	Software architecture	-	Java
-	Software Troubleshooting and Debugging	-	MySQL
-	Software Testing	-	React
-	Adaptability	-	GitHub
-	Python'	-	GitHub Actions

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Swedish (Work Proficiency)
- Arabic (Native)